<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title></title>
	<link href="https://facklambda.dev/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://facklambda.dev"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://facklambda.dev/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>mineshaft gap</title>
		<published>2022-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://facklambda.dev/seven/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://facklambda.dev/seven/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I rewatched &lt;em&gt;Dr. Strangelove: Or How I Stopped Worrying and Learned to Love the Bomb&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; along with my partner and a close friend, neither of which had seen the movie before. The movie satirizes the bureaucratic, process oriented mindset of cold war era politicians and military men, and remains both prescient and relevant to this day. There&#x27;s a scene in the movie where the great men are panicking over a percieved &amp;quot;mineshaft gap&amp;quot;. Many actions in the cold war were driven by the paranoid minds in charge of the military-industrial-inferiority complex. Every percieved advantage the other side had was deemed a &amp;quot;gap&amp;quot;, in the movie we watch them decry the &amp;quot;missile gap&amp;quot;, the &amp;quot;doomsday machine gap&amp;quot;, and finally the &amp;quot;mineshaft gap&amp;quot;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mind the gap...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;d like to preface this by saying I&#x27;m not trying to make any argument or convince any reader to change their outlooks, I just wanted to write down the way I&#x27;ve observed things play out during the pandemic. I&#x27;m writing for writing&#x27;s own sake. I&#x27;m not trying to make this a screed for or against anyone&#x27;s particular level of risk aversion. I just want to jot down an idle thought I had sometime last year, that has been rattling around in my head ever since. By now, if you know me IRL, you should understand where I land on this topic.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the global COVID-19 pandemic has drawn on, my friends and I have naturally segregated into our own little groups, each of which exhibiting varying levels of precautionary measures. Personally, I&#x27;m willing to adapt to my most cautious friend&#x27;s requirements, despite my own opinions that N95 masks and ventilation&#x2F;air filtration are sufficient, I know people who have been uncomfortable hanging out without covid tests and short quarantines beforehand. Thankfully, my partner and I are capable of accomodating these friends. Unfortunately this causes me to be somewhat discriminating of when&#x2F;where I hang out with friends who are less cautious.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The night of watching Dr Strangelove, much adult beverages were consumed, and our friend was inebriated enough to take up our offer to crash on our couch rather than venture home. Our friend woke up the next day and shared with us a humorous dream they had: &lt;em&gt;It was that I had made an announcement at the end of the night that I had already been ill with covid nearly a year earlier&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe my friend was cut short from finishing their thoughts either by my own questioning about what to have for breakfast, or our collective laughter. But I assumed the conclusion was that &lt;em&gt;I was just keeping up appearances to be able to maintain actively hanging out with my friend&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I thought that was very cute and endearing, but I&#x27;m confident I would have told my friends if I was ill with covid, and it wouldn&#x27;t change my level of caution towards the disease. As an aside, thankfully neither my partner nor I have caught covid roughly 3 years into this global pandemic, and I&#x27;m somewhat proud of that. But it brought to mind my previous thoughts of how during the course of this pandemic maybe we&#x27;ve all been collectively matching our own social circle&#x27;s expectations of safety.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to the &amp;quot;mineshaft gap&amp;quot;; I wondered if there was some element of &amp;quot;runaway&amp;quot; precautionary measures, so to say? And if that&#x27;s the case, is there also the inverse reaction of throwing caution to the wind? These two things are somewhat incompatible in the sense that overlap between the groups cannot exist cohesively. Are my more cautious friends actually cautious because they perceive me as being cautious and am I more cautions because I perceive my friends as more cautious... ad infinitum... ? Are people who throw caution to the wind only doing so because people in their social circle are throwing caution to the wind, yadda yadda yadda... Maybe I have just fixated on a tiny cultural signifier here, which is actually just a microcosm how how societies and social groupings naturally arrange themselves? Some folks might&#x27;ve been coerced in some ways to participate in social groupins they themselves haven&#x27;t chosen, the same way the B-52 crewmen were ordered to execute Wing Attack Plan R. Or maybe some folks enthusiasticaly embraced their assigned social grouping similary to Major T. J. Kong.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#x27;ve found yourself reading this with a similar expression as Group Captain Lionel Mandrake to Brigadier General Jack D. Ripper, and saying &amp;quot;I don&#x27;t follow&amp;quot;, then you&#x27;re probably in good company, thanks for reading.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>bust</title>
		<published>2022-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://facklambda.dev/six/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://facklambda.dev/six/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve recently been working on a fun project that should be a useful general-utility CLI app that can parse &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;gtfs.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;GTFS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; data for arbitrary transit providers (so long as they publish GTFS data!). I would like to roll this project into a bigger one for displaying timestables on an actual display.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project is currently named &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;facklambda&#x2F;bust&quot;&gt;&#x27;bust&#x27;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; which is a bit crass, but I like it so I&#x27;m sticking with it for the time being.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently the major dependencies of the app are &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;rust-transit&#x2F;gtfs-structure&quot;&gt;gtfs_structure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;clap-rs&#x2F;clap&quot;&gt;clap&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I will likely need to write some code that will be heavily reliant on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;seanmonstar&#x2F;reqwest&quot;&gt;reqwest&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in order to implement a feature that polls transit provider specific APIs (in this case, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;svc.metrotransit.org&#x2F;swagger&#x2F;index.html?urls.primaryName=NexTrip%20API%20-%20v2&quot;&gt;metrotransit&#x27;s nextripv2 api&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently I&#x27;m facing a problem with parsing the gtfs data in a timely manner. On my Raspberry Pi it takes about 30 seconds to parse the gtfs data into structs and the print out statistics regarding them. I believe this can be fine tuned, but don&#x27;t know exactly how at this time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;greetz to fellow bus riding friends, the strange amount of european transit app developers who like to use Rust, my partner V for putting up with my &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Rubber_duck_debugging&quot;&gt;rubber duck debugging&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>beerlicht pt 2</title>
		<published>2022-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://facklambda.dev/five/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://facklambda.dev/five/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve made leaps and bounds of progress on this project once I decided to start a bit smaller!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than being a bit over-ambitious, which is learning rust without much foundation on a relatively new embedded system (ESP32-C3) with relatively little documentation (it&#x27;s vastly improved since my last blog post). I readjusted my ambitions and settled on a more realistic goal of getting it all to run on a raspberry pi.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parts list so far:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;ESP32-C3&lt;&#x2F;del&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi 2b+ (running raspbian)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;string of 25 WS2812b LEDs&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25 glass bottles&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a milk crate&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 dupont wires&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After spending a few months hoarding glass beverage bottles, I finally amassed the proper amount of correctly sized bottles to fit a 5 by 5 grid in the milk crate. Cutting the daisychained strip of 50 WS2812b LEDs in half and placing one of each of the 25 LEDs into the mouth of each bottle was very simple. Hooking them up to the raspberry pi also proved to be simple, just direct connect the corresponding wires to a 5v pin, a SPI GPIO pin, and a ground pin.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-code&quot;&gt;The Code:&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m pretty new to writing rust code, and embedded electronics, but I have a basic knowledge of most concepts involved. I again had to recalibrate my expectations for this project. There&#x27;s no way I&#x27;m going to get up and running very quickly if I try to code this all myself, so I&#x27;m leaning heavily on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;phip1611&#x2F;ws2818-rgb-led-spi-driver&quot;&gt;Philipp Schuster&#x27;s very simple ws281x led driver rust code&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. This got me up and running with a nice set of examples and demo code that I could rely on for a quick dopamine rush (I particularly like the way the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;phip1611&#x2F;ws2818-rgb-led-spi-driver&#x2F;blob&#x2F;main&#x2F;examples&#x2F;src&#x2F;bin&#x2F;nxn-pulsating-square.rs&quot;&gt;pulsating square demo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; looks).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of writing this post, beerlicht&#x27;s published code still just a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;facklambda&#x2F;beerlicht&quot;&gt;repo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; containing Philipp&#x27;s code.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next steps for this project will be writing the networking code and the logic that lights each light up based on network activity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;greetz to Philipp, V, and all my friends who&#x27;ve been subjected to me showing this off.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>beerlicht</title>
		<published>2021-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://facklambda.dev/four/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://facklambda.dev/four/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve started on a fun little art project based losely off of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.noisebridge.net&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Flaschen_Taschen&quot;&gt;noisebridge&#x27;s Flaschen Taschen&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;matelight.rocks&quot;&gt;c-base&#x27;s Mate-Light&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My twist on the project is that it will be an ambient light that reacts to traffic on the local network (and maybe even the wide area network).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parts list so far:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ESP32-C3&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;string of 25 WS2812b LEDs&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25 glass bottles&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a milk crate&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 dupont wires&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;greetz to Philipp, V, and all my friends who&#x27;ve been subjected to me showing this off.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>git gud</title>
		<published>2021-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://facklambda.dev/three/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://facklambda.dev/three/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve moved. Twice. since the last post on here. So much for daily updates. it&#x27;s been 2 years not much has changed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m going to go through the TODOs list I had previously created and narrow things down, update what I&#x27;ve done, and maybe prune things I&#x27;m no longer interested in doing from it. As you can tell this site has gotten a bit stale (and has changed locations, as far as domains are concerned lol).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;todo&quot;&gt;TODO&lt;&#x2F;h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some vague car hacking project
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OBD-II telemetry&#x2F;DIY Lo-Jack&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appsec&#x2F;netsec pentesting of in car infotainment units (*hilariously insecu$&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CAN bus hacking:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to enable modifications of dashboard&#x2F;infotainment gauges&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to translate CAN signals from non-stock components for the stock gauge$&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to build racing sym setups using junkyard car parts
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have everythiNg I need to build a USB plug in Mazda3 dashboard.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did nothing from here beyond discovering some cool folks here in North Minneapolis are the proprietors of the Macchina.cc CAN suite.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wrenching on a car
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one of those projects were i consistently use the incorrect tools (hacksaw$&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I desparately want to build a racecar
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My &#x27;89 AW11 MR2 needs some resto work
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have a K swap entirely planned and priced out, however I don&#x27;t t$&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My &#x27;16 BRZ needs &lt;strong&gt;MORE POWAHHHHHH&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LS swap is something I&#x27;m saving up for.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LIGHTNING&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LIGHTNING&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LIGHTNING&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey speaking of lightning, I&#x27;m fully electric car pilled now.
Squaring wanting a race car with also wanting to not live on a dying planet has caused me a considerable amount of cognitive dissonance. And with the last 2 years of pandemic related lockdowns and general hermitage, I didn&#x27;t really drive much.
The BRZ has proven to be a fun car, but new cars fucking suck to work on, too much fiddly shit that I&#x27;m prone to breaking.
I&#x27;m planning on taking my rustbucket MR2 and putting a Nissan Leaf engine in it. It&#x27;s been done before, and frankly looks like less of a headache than trying to cram some fucking Honda K-series engine in there. Finally have a garage, and some spare cash to throw at this kind of thing.
I&#x27;ve satiated my urges to wrench on shit by helping my buddy j3s with his Saturn Ion, helping my sibling a little with a Isuzu Hombre, and memorizing the entire wiring diagram of the passenger side of my Subaru BRZ (THAT FUCKIN SUCKED YO) &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;arcade cabinet
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;basically a fan project for the original Risk of Rain game, my alltime fav$&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want to make a 4 player standup cabinet, with lots of LEDs, an animated $&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using a mod loader I wanted to create an API for triggering animations and$
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this requires programming knowledge slightly beyond my skill level atm&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;woodworking!
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gotta buy the proper tools lol&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project got the best of me most of this summer, however I quickly realized my dream arcade cabinet was far to big to fit in anywhere at my house, and I quickly grew disillusioned, because I didn&#x27;t want to make some crappy pedestal style arcade that would need hooked up to some random video output.
I&#x27;m sure I&#x27;ll revisit this, but maybe when I&#x27;m more apt to donate a grand worth of arcade shit to a space where it would be appreciated.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;general programming stuff lol
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rust is really fun so far I&#x27;ve written a tiny bit&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Done quite a lot here.
- something on cloudflare workers would be fun to build
- i don&#x27;t like maintaining servers&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MY FRIEND RECOMMENDED ME FOR A JOB WHERE I DO THIS FOR A LIVING LOL (lambda)
- a towerdefense game&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;still haven&#x27;t done this, still want to do this
- embedded stuff for a bunch of the above projects&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;been playing with an esp32-c3 and making leds blink so hell yeah i&#x27;ve made progress here
- a mobile app that does something fun idk what yet&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;made a proof of concept app using flutter that gamified not charging your phone. :shrug: it was for ludum dare
- some embedded firmware stuff for open-source bootloaders, on either androi$&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;nothing to show for this
- demoscene stuff, just absolutely gives me goosebumps every time i interact$
- there was a project that enabled opensource controll of my RGB keyboar$
- same with android bootloader animations
- apparently bootloader animations across any opensource stuff (coreboot$&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;basically got drunk with roomates and just taught them about demoscene culture lmao&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
- plugin for zola (the static site generator that makes this site) to enable$&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;highkey fell off of this
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;building a new pc&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOPE LOL, CHIP SHORTAGES, CRYPTOCURRENCY FUELED SCALPERS. ARM SoCs are the future anyways. replace your desktop with a server somewhere it&#x27;ll get better connectivity and carbon neutral power&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;streaming stuff on twitch&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Done. check me out at twitch.tv&#x2F;facklambda&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;working with my friends on cyberia.club significanly more&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oops, I&#x27;ve kinda avoided&#x2F;fallen out of touch with cyberia. They recently got a physical space that I will try to show up to more often.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reading more, i&#x27;m a news junkie, but i&#x27;d like to read more &lt;em&gt;shudder&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; Theory wi$&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did an alright job of this, finished the Three-Body Problem, started reading #Accelerate: The Accelerationist Reader&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blogging, dumping some thoughts into a journal anyone can read&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;lol, evidently not&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;general cypherpunkery&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;idk, got an assload of friends to join Signal during the Minneapolis uprisings&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;getting certified to use the machine shop at the Hack Factory&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;tf2 engineer voice&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &amp;quot;NOPE&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3d printing (car accessories mostly)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s still some interest here, but damn it&#x27;s one of those things where I ask myself: &amp;quot;does the world really need more random plastic junk?&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;netsec
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;websec seems to be my primary talent area, since i work with webapps all d$&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;appsec interests me a lot as well since that typically is the venue for re$&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;now, websec is a talent area, but I&#x27;m truly more fascinated by the fields of Trusted Computing, systems level isolation, hypervisors and stuff like homomorphic encryption. So not much progress on this front.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any of this stuff also sounds interesting to you, or you wanna talk about it,$&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;d like to thank my friend j3s for listening to me breathlessly talk about certain tech stacks and connecting the dots from there to an awesome job opportunity that I&#x27;ve since taken. My life has improved in ways you cannot imagine, thanks friend.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;greetz to v, wendy, jo, jamin, j3s, vvesley, johnnie, nyx, junk, nildicit, kaworu, shoggoth, starless, elisha, cass, forest, lief, aimless, mc_crash, skh, kurt, justin, taylor, jackson, pearl&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fuckingz to all my former landlords, cryptocurrency miners using fossil fuels, hoarders, even more unfinished projects, and the entire concept of procrastination.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>hello, friend.</title>
		<published>2020-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://facklambda.dev/one/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://facklambda.dev/one/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#x27;Hello, friend?&amp;quot; That&#x27;s lame. Maybe I should give you a name. But that&#x27;s a slippery slope. You&#x27;re only in my head. We have to remember that. Shit. It&#x27;s actually happened. I&#x27;m talking to an imaginary person. What I&#x27;m about to tell you is top secret. A conspiracy bigger than all of us. There&#x27;s a powerful group of people out there that are secretly running the world. I&#x27;m talking about the guys no one knows about. The guys that are invisible. The top one percent of the top one percent. The guys that play God without permission. And now I think they&#x27;re following me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this is my first blog post. Pretty damn underwhelming I&#x27;ll tell ya what... My goals for this project are to attempt to maintain an average of 1 blog post per day, about either my thoughts on politics, news, projects, and problems I feel are worthy of writing about.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be worth noting that I&#x27;ve been hyping myself up to make a public blog for about 4 years now. Unfortunately I have a habit letting my perfectionism get the best of me, and allowing myself to procrastinate things indefinitely. I realized I needed to just bite the bullet and get this thing started.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here I am, starting a blog post with a quote from the first episode of one of my favorite TV series, Mr. Robot. I&#x27;ve consumed a lot of media during the quarantine, and I&#x27;ve finally hit the point where I&#x27;m completely bored of that. I definitely feel the urge to just create something, anything. And at this point a blog post is probably the least embarrasing online presence I can curate. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;greetz to v, kurt, jo, j3s, vvesley, nyx, junk, nildicit, kaworu, shoggoth, starless, cass, forest, aimless, mc_crash, skh, twitter mufos, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cyberia.club&quot;&gt;cyberia.club&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; crew&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fuckingz to anyone that refuses to wear a mask&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>TODO</title>
		<published>2020-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://facklambda.dev/two/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://facklambda.dev/two/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week I told my landlord that I&#x27;m moving out. &lt;em&gt;Sidenote: I&#x27;m currently looking for a place to move into by October 1st :) if you know of anything, hmu.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; In this process, I have begun to take inventory of all the stuff I&#x27;ve accumulated during my occupation of this unit, and I see a lot of half-assed attempts at unfinished projects. So in the interest of no-one, I am going to make a public TODO list of random bullshit I&#x27;d like to work on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large portion of my projects seem to be heavily influenced by my itch to work on embedded electronics, but are hamstrung my complete unwillingness to learn anything about electronics, eletrical signals, and my utter disdain for purchasing the proper equipment. As far as these projects go, they seem to be mostly unified around building an arcade cabinet and sniffing&#x2F;hacking CAN bus stuff from my car&#x27;s OBD-II port.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway enough weird excuses and whining about why I haven&#x27;t done any of these yet. Here&#x27;s an insanely unstructured list.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;todo&quot;&gt;TODO&lt;&#x2F;h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some vague car hacking project
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OBD-II telemetry&#x2F;DIY Lo-Jack&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appsec&#x2F;netsec pentesting of in car infotainment units (&lt;em&gt;hilariously insecure in older cars&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CAN bus hacking:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to enable modifications of dashboard&#x2F;infotainment gauges&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to translate CAN signals from non-stock components for the stock gauges to interpret&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to build racing sym setups using junkyard car parts 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have everythiNg I need to build a USB plug in Mazda3 dashboard.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wrenching on a car
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one of those projects were i consistently use the incorrect tools (hacksawing off my rusty sway bar?!? &lt;strong&gt;Yes.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I desparately want to build a racecar
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My &#x27;89 AW11 MR2 needs some resto work
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have a K swap entirely planned and priced out, however I don&#x27;t think this car is in shape to do so.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My &#x27;16 BRZ needs &lt;strong&gt;MORE POWAHHHHHH&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LS swap is something I&#x27;m saving up for.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LIGHTNING&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LIGHTNING&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LIGHTNING&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;arcade cabinet
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;basically a fan project for the original Risk of Rain game, my alltime favorite videogame.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want to make a 4 player standup cabinet, with lots of LEDs, an animated tickerboard for high-scores, and some leds or tiny screen inlays on the control panel&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using a mod loader I wanted to create an API for triggering animations and lighting effects from the game&#x27;s state.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this requires programming knowledge slightly beyond my skill level atm&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;woodworking!
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gotta buy the proper tools lol&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;general programming stuff lol
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rust is really fun so far I&#x27;ve written a tiny bit.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;something on cloudflare workers would be fun to build
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i don&#x27;t like maintaining servers&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a towerdefense game&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;embedded stuff for a bunch of the above projects&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a mobile app that does something fun idk what yet&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some embedded firmware stuff for open-source bootloaders, on either android devices or chromeos devices&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;demoscene stuff, just absolutely gives me goosebumps every time i interact with it, i know i would love this
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there was a project that enabled opensource controll of my RGB keyboard&#x27;s LEDs and i thought that&#x27;d be a fun target&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;same with android bootloader animations&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apparently bootloader animations across any opensource stuff (coreboot, oreboot, uboot, libreboot)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plugin for zola (the static site generator that makes this site) to enable webmentions and other indieweb stuff&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;building a new pc&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;streaming stuff on twitch&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;working with my friends on cyberia.club significanly more&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reading more, i&#x27;m a news junkie, but i&#x27;d like to read more &lt;em&gt;shudder&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; Theory with a capital T.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blogging, dumping some thoughts into a journal anyone can read&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;general cypherpunkery&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;getting certified to use the machine shop at the Hack Factory&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3d printing (car accessories mostly)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;netsec
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;websec seems to be my primary talent area, since i work with webapps all day long.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;appsec interests me a lot as well since that typically is the venue for reversing and ~~hacking~~liberating embedded electronics and iot stuff&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any of this stuff also sounds interesting to you, or you wanna talk about it, or you wanna even work on it, feel free to hmu on the matrix network @fack:cyberia.club. The computer club I&#x27;m part of hosts a homeserver available to the public, they&#x27;re linked below. :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;greetz to v, kurt, jordan, cory, kev, ash, jo, j3s, vvesley, nyx, junk, nildicit, kaworu, shoggoth, starless, cass, forest, aimless, mc_crash, skh, twitter mufos, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cyberia.club&quot;&gt;cyberia.club&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; crew&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fuckingz to my current landlord, hoarders, unfinished projects, and clutter&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
